<title>Michael Phelps breaks Olympic record with 4x200m freestyle gold</title>
<content><div role="main"><p itemprop="description">    Michael Phelps won a record 19th Olympic medal as 
    
<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/olympics/2012/live-video/p00w2y9r?tc=2012-07-31T19%3A53%3A07-00%3A00">he helped the US team to gold in the 4x200m freestyle relay.</a> 

</p>
  
          <p>    It means Phelps also picked up his 15th gold medal as he swam the anchor leg to complete a winning time of six minutes 59.70 seconds ahead of France in second and China in third.
</p>
  
          <p>    Ryan Lochte put the US team in total control with a blistering first leg and they barely lost their advantage. 
</p>
  
          <p>    Phelps overtakes Russian gymnast Larisa Latynina who won 18 medals.
</p>
  
          <p>    Phelps still has three more races at London 2012 and could establish a record that would be difficult for anyone to beat.
</p>
  
          <p>    "It has been a pretty amazing career," he said, "but we still have a couple races to go."
</p>
  
          <p>    Just minutes before the relay victory, the 15-time gold medallist had claimed his 18th Olympic medal with a silver behind South Africa's Chad le Clos in the 200m butterfly.
</p>
  
          <p>    Le Clos came from behind to touch the wall in one minute 52.96 seconds, just 0.05secs ahead of Phelps.
</p>
  
          <p>    "Obviously I would have liked to have had a better outcome in the 200m fly. I was on the receiving end of getting touched off. 
</p>
  
          <p>    "Chad swam a great race and I've gotten to know him over the past year and he's a hard worker, tough competitor and a racer and you know it was obviously my last one I would have liked to have won, but you know one minute 53 seconds isn't a terrible time, if you look at the picture of it it's a decent time.
</p>
  
          <p>    The 15th gold did not take long to come, however, the American team had a lead of four seconds going into the last leg of the 4x200m freestyle relay - mainly thanks to Lochte's fast start.
</p>
  
          <p>    At the end of the race, the four men huddled together in an emotional moment.
</p>
  
          <p>    "I thanked those guys for helping me get to this moment," Phelps said. 
</p>
  
          <p>    "I told those guys I wanted a big lead. I was like, 'You better give me a big lead going into the last lap,' and they gave it to me. I just wanted to hold on. I thanked them for being able to allow me to have this moment."
</p>
  
          <p>    Great Britain's team of Robbie Renwick, Ieuan Lloyd, Rob Bale and Ross Davenport finished sixth.
</p>
  
          <p>    <strong>    More to follow.
</strong>
</p>
  
    

			
						
			<div>
    <h3>Also related to this story</h3>
    
    <ul>
	                    <li>
                







    	

	
	<a data-published="1343762382455" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/olympics/18902357">
                                                        Le Clos stuns Phelps in 200m fly
                
                                    
                    <span></span>
                    
                            		
		</a>
		
	
					<span>
				<span>31 Jul 2012</span>
		
			<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/olympics/2012/sports/swimming">Swimming</a>
	
			</span>
	
	
            </li>
                    <li>
                







    	

	
	<a data-published="1343542844796" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/olympics/19034415">
                                                        Can Phelps recover from 'upsetting' defeat?
                
                                    
                    <span></span>
                    
                            		
		</a>
		
	
					<span>
				<span>29 Jul 2012</span>
		
			<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/olympics/2012/sports/swimming">Swimming</a>
	
			</span>
	
	
            </li>
                    <li>
                







    	

	
	<a data-published="1343593260680" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/olympics/18904593">
                                                        France beat Phelps's US in relay
                
                                    
                    <span></span>
                    
                            		
		</a>
		
	
					<span>
				<span>29 Jul 2012</span>
		
			<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/olympics/2012/sports/swimming">Swimming</a>
	
			</span>
	
	
            </li>
            </ul>
</div>
 

			
			<div>
								<h3>Share this story</h3>
				    <div>
                    <div>
                <div>
                    <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/modules/sharetools/share?url=http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/olympics/18902418&amp;appId=sport">Share this page</a>
                </div>
            </div>
                        <div>
                <ul>
                    <li><a href="?print=true">print</a></li>
                </ul>
            </div>
                                        
                <div>
                    
                </div>
                
            
            </div>
            
    
							</div>
			
							
				<div>
					
				</div>
				
				
					</div></content>